Casey Kerrick



Qualification Summary

Casey Kerrick is a Consultant with a strong background in communication and problem solving. Attained his B.S. in three years from an elite engineering college. Worked as a full stack developer for various clients, including on a class III project in the healthcare sector. Comfortable working with both small and large Agile teams. Very experienced with pair programming, team collaboration, and team problem solving. Experience communicating directly with clients in order to gather requirements and write stories.

Skills Summary

Industry Experience: Construction Equipment Fleet Management, Healthcare, Hair Salon Software

Competencies: Pair Programming, Requirements Gathering, Continuous Deployment/Continuous

Integration, Testing, Debugging, Problem Solving

Languages: Node.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Angular 8, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS3, Java,

SOL

Software/Tools: IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Lens, Sublime Text, MS Excel, MS Office

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Operating Systems: Windows, OS X, Linux

Experience

Daugherty Business Solutions, Bloomington, MN **Consultant**

May 2021 - Present

ProPoint Solutions LLC, Minneapolis, MN *Full Stack Software Engineer*

Feb 2020 - Apr 2021

Learned several new technologies to get up to speed in a challenging and fast paced work environment, and stay on top of a large amount of concurrent projects. Worked with client salons in order to gather requirements for new projects and reports.

- <u>Public API</u> Created a federated GraphQL API that returns stored client data, so they can compile reports. Also houses endpoints for internal use.
 - o Managed remote jobs using Kubernetes that sent salon payment data to an external payment system.
 - o Connected the API to both a legacy MySQL database and a new MongoDB database.

Used: Apollo, Node.js, TypeScript, GraphQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Kubernetes, Lens, GraphQL Playground, Kibana, Docker

- New Legacy App Skeleton Took a legacy PHP app built with frames and loaded the pages into iframes created by a React.js skeleton.
 - Created new API endpoints to support shift to Cognito login
 - O Displayed or hid tabs based on user authorization
 - Structured the app so that each tab could have its iframe replaced with a React.js component for a seamless user experience.

Used: Amazon Cognito, Node.js, React Native, TypeScript, GraphQL, Material UI, PHP, Docker

- <u>CSV Reporting</u> Rewrote old PHP reports in Node.js, simplifying the logic and greatly speeding up query time.
 - Reports went from several thousand lines of PHP and about an 8 hour runtime to 100 lines of Node.js that ran in 15 minutes
 - Worked together to create a new reporting framework so future reports are easier to add Used: Node.js, TypeScript, PHP

Software Engineering Professionals, Carmel, IN *Full Stack Software Engineer*

Sep 2017 - Jan 2020

Worked as a consultant on a variety of projects, with a strong emphasis on pair programming and collaboration. Worked closely with a design team to ensure the client received the best product possible.

- <u>Construction Equipment Fleet Management</u> Rewrote both frontend and backend legacy software in order to simplify and modernize it.
 - Utilized Google Maps to create a page that visually tracked geofences (virtual boundaries based on global coordinates) and curfews on equipment in order to prevent it from being stolen.
 - Split a legacy Java Spring monolith API into a network of microservices and AWS Lambdas in order to improve latency.

Used: React Redux, Node.js, TypeScript, Java, Java Spring, AWS Lambda, Kibana, JUnit, Mockito

- <u>Diabetes Health Monitoring Site</u> A website where doctors can monitor and manage patients with type II diabetes who require insulin.
 - o Team created both a frontend and backend, and pulled data from Smart on FHIR
 - O Used the patient data to create graphs and charts representing the patient's progress, and make suggestions for how the patient should eat and how much insulin they should take to manage their diabetes better.

Used: Angular 8, TypeScript, Smart on FHIR

Recognitions and Certifications

Crucial Conversations Training

Education

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology, Terre Haute, Indiana (2017) B.S. Computer Science